# **Justin Looman**

(585) 545-8741 | jlooman20002@gmail.com

To review my creative content, please visit: <a href="https://people.rit.edu/jdl9046/Website/index.html">https://people.rit.edu/jdl9046/Website/index.html</a>

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Dedicated, passionate, and creative professional with many years personally intrigued in the games industry. Currently a 4th year student pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Gaming and Development at RIT. Acquiring producing, programming and technical skills. Currently a part of the <u>MAGIC Maker Program</u> as a production manager/team lead for <u>Ninjas on Trampolines</u>.

#### **EDUCATION:**

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Science, Game Design and Development

GPA: 3.2

Expected: December 2024

Related Courses: Production Studio, Game Design & Development (I&II), Data Structures & Algorithms for Games & Simulations, Rich Media Web Application Development (I&II), Casual Games Development, Artificial Intelligence

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Unreal Blueprints

Tools: Miro, Trello, Clickup, Visual Studios 2019, Unity, Unreal, XR, Blender, MonoGame, Photoshop CC, Git, Maya

#### **PROJECTS:**

# Ninjas on Trampolines: (MAGIC Maker Program, Spring 2024)

- Production manager/team lead, UI/UX developer.
- Used Miro to create timelines and wireframes, along with Trello to create task cards.

#### Changeling VR: (Entrepreneurial co-op, June 2023 - August 2023)

- Team lead for Father's level. Used Clickup to create and assign tasks to members.
- 10x'ed frame rates of the level, made a clear path for players to traverse, and created better interactive puzzles.

### Icarus VR: (IGME 450, Spring 2023)

- Responsible for leading the team's direction, designing user interface, and level layouts.
- Used Trello to create and assign tasks.

#### Helpless: (Pirate Software Jam, January 2024)

• 2 week jam. Team lead and UI/UX. Set up GDD for timeline and Trello for task management.

## Exploding Apples: (RIT Game Dev Club game jam, February 2024)

46 hour jam, solo game.

## Doodle Day: (Game jam w/ Wolfjaw Studios, November 2023)

• 24 hour jam. Team lead, artist. Placed 3rd overall. Combination of Trello and a whiteboard for task management.

### Al Pathfinding: (IGME 560, Spring 2023)

• Using A\* and Dikstra, created a program to pathfind between two points on a grid.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# Ninjas on Trampolines (co-op) - Team Lead

January 2024 to May 2024

- Team lead. Used trello and miro to bring art, sound, and code together in a seamless pipeline.
- Worked closely with artists to create UI for the game, then implemented UX.

# Changeling (co-op) - Team Lead

June 2023 to August 2023

- Led a team of 5 to redesign a level to better represent the game's feel and looks.
- Worked with other departments to incorporate new art, sound and VFX into the level.

## Lowes - Fulfillment

June 2021 to August 2023

Provided efficient & friendly customer service, ensuring all orders completed and delivered in a timely manner.

#### Mark's Pizzeria - Insider

March 2020 to August 2021

- Exemplified excellent customer service. Efficiently received, produced, and delivered orders.
- Trained 6 new members on the logistics of pizza making.

#### **Western New York Referee Association** - Soccer Referee

March 2016 - August 2019

- Experienced in conflict resolution between younger players, parents & coaches regarding opinions on play calls.
- Capable of remaining calm in high pressure situations.